[Music] next js create fast search engine
[音乐]next js 创建快速搜索引擎
optimize react apps with zero configuration
优化零配置
a traditional react app is rendered client side where the browser starts
的反应应用程序传统的反应应用程序在客户端呈现，浏览器
with a shell of an html page lacking any rendered content from there
以 html 页面的外壳开始，缺少任何呈现的内容
the browser fetches the javascript file containing the react code to render
浏览器从那里获取包含反应代码的 javascript 文件 将
content to the page and make it interactive but there are
内容呈现到页面并使其具有交互性，但
two major drawbacks with client-side rendering
客户端呈现有两个主要缺点，
one the content is not reliably indexed by all search engines
一个是所有搜索引擎都不能可靠地索引内容
or read by social media link bots and two it can take longer to reach the
或被社交媒体链接机器人读取，二是到达第一个内容可能需要更长的时间
first contentful paint when a user first lands on the web page
当用户第一次登陆网页时绘制
next is a framework that allows you to build a react app but render the content
下一个是一个框架，它允许您构建一个反应应用程序，但
in advance on the server so the first thing a user or search bot
提前在服务器上呈现内容，因此用户或搜索机器人看到的第一件事是
sees is the fully rendered html after receiving this initial page
收到这个初始值后完全呈现的 html 页面
client-side rendering takes over and it works just like a traditional
客户端渲染接管，它就像传统的
react app it's the best of both worlds fully rendered content for bots highly
反应应用程序一样工作，它是两全其美的完全渲染的机器人内容高度
interactive content for users inside of a next project you have a
int 在下一个项目中为用户提供的 eractive 内容您有一个
pages directory each javascript file defined here
pages 目录这里定义的每个 javascript 文件都
exports a react component that represents a route in the application
导出一个反应组件，该组件表示应用程序中的一个路由，
in other words the file structure here mirrors the actual urls that the user
换句话说，这里的文件结构反映了用户将导航到的实际 url
will navigate to and next provides its own router to make
并接下来提供 它自己的路由器可以
navigation seamless but the real magic comes into play when
无缝导航，但是当我们谈论数据获取时，真正的魔力开始发挥作用，
we talk about data fetching because next can perform multiple server
因为 next 可以从单个项目中执行多个服务器
rendering strategies from a single project
渲染策略
static generation or pre-rendering allows you to render your pages
静态生成或预渲染允许您
at build time each page or component can implement a function called
在构建时渲染页面每个页面或 组件可以实现一个名为
get static props it might fetch data from a cloud database then pass the data
get static props 的函数，它可以从云数据库中获取数据，然后将数据
as props to the component you can then build your app to render
作为 props 传递给组件，然后您可以构建您的应用程序以
out all the html locally and upload it to a storage bucket where
在本地呈现所有 html并将其上传到可以存储的存储桶
it can be easily cached by a cdn that works great for a blog or any kind
中 很容易被一个 CDN 缓存，它适用于博客或任何类型
of app where the data doesn't change often
的应用程序，其中数据不经常更改，
but if the data does change often you can implement server side rendering
但如果数据确实 c 经常你可以实现服务器端渲染
which builds the html page each time it's requested by the user in
，每次用户请求它时构建html页面
the component we implement data fetching with the get server side props function
在组件中我们使用get服务器端props函数实现数据获取，
instead of running at build time this function runs at request time
而不是在构建时运行这个函数在请求时运行，
that means the page will fetch the latest data on the server each time a
这意味着页面每次有新请求进来时都会在服务器上获取最新数据，这
new request comes in that's great for pages with rapidly
对于数据快速变化的页面来说非常有用，
changing data but maybe you want something in between yet another option
但也许你想要介于两者之间的东西另一个选项
is incremental static regeneration by simply adding a revalidate option to get
是增量静态再生，只需添加一个重新验证选项来获取
static props next can regenerate a page whenever a
静态道具next 可以重新生成 每当有
new request comes in within a certain time interval this has
新请求在某个时间间隔内进入时的页面这
been next js in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos
已经是 100 秒内的下一个 js如果您想看到更多这样的短视频，
like this make sure to subscribe and hit the like button
请确保订阅并点击“like”按钮
then open up the s code and get ready to go beyond 100 seconds with a full
然后打开 s 代码并准备好超过 100 秒，
breakdown of next before we get going i'd like to point
在我们开始之前完全分解下一个我想
out that i'm working on a full react next firebase course which i hope to
指出我正在努力对下一个火力基地课程做出全面反应 我希望在
have finally finished by the end of january
1 月底之前最终完成，
which will be available to fireship pro members my goal over the next few
这将提供给 fireship pro会员我在接下来的
minutes is to teach you the fundamentals of next
几分钟内的目标是教你 next 的基础知识，
while also explaining the complexities of server-side rendering
同时解释服务器端渲染的复杂性，
to follow along open up the terminal and run npx
以跟随 open 打开终端并运行 npx
create next app followed by the name of your app and if you get lost at any
create next app 后跟应用程序的名称，如果您在任何时候迷路，请
point make sure to grab the source code on
确保获取 github 或 fireship io 上的源代码，
github or fireship io let's open up the project in vs code and
让我们在 vs code 中打开项目，
then go into the package.json file in development the only script we need
然后进入包 .json 文件在开发中我们需要担心的唯一脚本
to worry about is dev which you can execute by running npm run
是 dev，您可以通过从命令行运行 npm run
dev from the command line which will run our
dev来执行它，它将
app on localhost 3000 that should give you the default
在 localhost 3000 上运行我们的应用程序，这应该
boilerplate in the browser now before we get into the react code
在我们得到之前在浏览器中为您提供默认样板在 react 代码
there's a few things that i want to point out first in the styles directory
中，我想首先在样式目录中指出一些事情，在
here you'll notice how next supports css modules
这里您会注意到 next 如何
in the globals file you can define styles that apply to the entire
在 globals 文件中支持 css 模块，您可以定义适用于 e 的样式 ntire
application but in other files with dot module you
应用程序，但在其他带有 dot 模块的文件中，您
can define classes that only apply to a specific route or component
可以定义仅适用于特定路由或组件的类，
and you don't have to worry about coming up with a bunch of unique class names or
并且您不必担心在管理样式时会想出一堆唯一的类名或
naming conventions when managing your styles
命名约定。
if you want to use styles from a certain module you just import the style sheet
要使用来自某个模块的样式，您只需
in your javascript then reference your styles in jsx as if
在 javascript 中导入样式表，然后在 jsx 中引用您的样式，就好像
the styles were a javascript object that's pretty awesome but from there
这些样式是一个非常棒的 javascript 对象一样，但是从那里
let's shift our attention over to the pages directory
让我们将注意力转移到
inside this directory we define all the pages and routes for the application
我们定义的这个目录中的 pages 目录应用程序
at the highest level we have this underscore app.js file which is like the
的最高级别的所有页面和路由 我们有这个下划线 app.js 文件，它就像
main entry point into the app in other words every individual page
应用程序的主要入口点，换句话说，每个单独的页面
will start from this template currently the application only has one
都将从这个模板开始当前应用程序只有一个
page which points to the root url and is defined by the component in the
页面指向 到根 url并由 index.js 文件中的组件定义，
index.js file when a user navigates to this url next
当用户导航到该 url 时，接下来
will find the default export which is a react component
将找到默认导出，即
in this file so every file or page in your application
这个文件中的 react 组件，所以你的应用程序中的每个文件或页面都
needs to have one default export to demonstrate this further
需要有一个默认导出来进一步演示这一点
let's create our first route in the pages directory create a new file called
让我们在 pages 目录中创建我们的第一个路由创建一个名为 hello.js 的新文件，
hello.js then we can define the content of this
然后我们可以通过以下方式定义此
page by exporting a default react component from it
页面的内容 从那里导出一个默认的反应组件，
from there we can go back to the browser and navigate to localhost 3000
我们可以返回浏览器并导航到 localhost 3000
slash hello and we should get the content of that component
slash hello，我们应该得到该组件的内容，
congratulations you just built your first web page with next
恭喜你刚刚构建了你的第一个网页，
but now let's imagine a route that's a little more complex we have a cars route
但现在让我们想象一条路线是稍微复杂一点，我们有一条汽车路线
that should show a list of cars then an infinite number of cars that
，它应该显示汽车列表，然后
might be dynamically generated under that url we can implement a
可能会在该 url 下动态生成无限数量的汽车，我们可以
dynamic route like that by first creating a cars directory then
通过首先创建一个汽车目录然后
inside the directory we'll add an index.js file
在目录中实现这样的动态路线，我们将 添加一个index.js 文件
which will show the main list of cars then for each individual car
，该文件将显示汽车的主要列表，然后对于每辆单独的汽车，
we'll add a component that has a file name of brackets
我们将添加一个组件，该组件的文件名为括号
paramname dot js the brackets make this route dynamic
paramname dot js 括号使这条路线动态
which means anytime a user navigates to cars
，这意味着任何时候用户导航到汽车
slash whatever or cars slash tesla it will render the component in this
斜线或汽车斜线特斯拉它都会在这个
file to see that in action let's go ahead and implement the
文件中呈现组件以查看实际情况让我们继续并
component logic in the index file we'll just add a placeholder for the car's
在我们将添加的索引文件中实现组件逻辑
list for now but in the dynamic component we'll
现在是汽车列表的占位符，但在动态组件中，我们
import the use router hook from the next router
将从下一个路由器导入使用路由器钩子，
it allows us to access the query parameters from the url
它允许我们从
in this example the value is id but you can give it a name of whatever you want
本示例中的 url 访问查询参数，值是 id 但你可以给它一个名字 任何你想要的
and then we'll render that value out to the template now back in the browser
，然后我们将把这个值呈现给模板，现在回到浏览器中
if we go to the car's url it renders out the car's component
then if we add any string after the car's url it renders out the dynamic
component now one other thing you may have noticed
现在您可能在 pages 目录中注意到的另一件事
in the pages directory is this api directory
是这个 api目录，
so what is that all about the api directory is a special part of next
所以关于 api 目录的所有内容是 next 的一个特殊部分，
for setting up routes that will only apply to the server
用于设置仅适用于
that can be useful because the code you write here won't increase the
可以 b 的服务器的路由 e 很有用，因为您在此处编写的代码不会增加最终
client-side javascript bundle that needs to ultimately be sent over the network
需要通过网络发送的客户端 javascript 包
we're not going to get into api routes in this video but just know that it's a
我们不会在此视频中进入 api 路由，但只要知道这是一个
useful feature when you have work that needs to be done on the back end
有用的功能，当您 有需要在后端完成的工作，
or if you simply want to expose an api for your end users
或者如果您只是想为您的最终用户公开一个 API，
but now let's shift our attention over to the most valuable feature in next
但现在让我们将注意力转移到接下来最有价值的功能
which of course is data fetching next allows us to fetch data
上，当然接下来是数据获取允许我们获取数据
and render html on the server and again the benefit of doing that
并在服务器上渲染 html，这样做的好处
is that the end user gets rendered content quicker and the content can be
是最终用户可以更快地获得渲染的内容，并且
reliably crawled by search bots and social media link bots
搜索机器人和社交媒体链接机器人可以可靠地抓取内容
now when it comes to server rendering there are two main options
现在在服务器渲染方面有两个主要选项
static generation and server side rendering
静态 生成和服务器端渲染
static generation is also called pre-rendering because you generate all
静态生成也称为预渲染，因为您
the html at build time it makes life very simple
在构建时生成所有 html，它使生活变得非常简单，
because you generate a bunch of html files
因为您生成一堆 html文件
then upload them to a storage bucket or static host
然后上传 它们到存储桶或静态主机
and they can be delivered with very high performance over a cdn
，它们可以通过 CDN 以非常高的性能交付，
but there's a couple of big trade-offs here the first one is that your data may
但这里有几个很大的权衡，第一个是
become stale if the data on the server changes you
如果服务器上的数据发生变化，
need to rebuild and redeploy your site in order for those changes to be
你的数据可能会变得陈旧。 重建和重新部署您的网站以反映这些更改
reflected another important trait i have to think
我必须考虑的另一个重要特征
about is scale if your website has a million pages it'll be very slow and
是规模如果您的网站有一百万个页面，那么预渲染所有这些页面将非常缓慢且
difficult to pre-render all of them that makes static generation most
困难，这使得静态生成最多
well-suited for data that doesn't change often
非常适合不经常更改的数据
and for sites that have a relatively low number of total pages
以及总页数相对较少的网站，
a good example would be a blog because it might have a few hundred pages and
一个很好的例子是博客，因为它可能有几百页，而且
those pages likely don't change on a daily basis
这些页面可能不会每天都发生变化
let's go ahead and take a look at how we might implement static generation in
让我们继续看看我们如何
next in the car component let's imagine we
在汽车组件的 next 中实现静态生成让我们假设我们
need to fetch data from an external source
需要从
like a database or api to simulate that for the demo i've added a couple of json
数据库或 api 等外部源获取数据来模拟我添加了一个 c 的演示 将两个 json
files to the public directory we have a file that returns an array of
文件添加到公共目录我们有一个文件，该文件返回一个 id 数组，
ids then an individual response for each car which contains an image and
然后为每辆汽车提供一个单独的响应，其中包含有关汽车的图像和
other data about the car now we can fetch this data for the car
其他数据现在我们可以
component by implementing the get static props function inside the
通过实现 get static 为汽车组件获取这些数据 组件文件中的 props 函数，
component file when you build your site next will
当您接下来构建站点时，将
automatically call this function then send the result as props to the
自动调用此函数，然后将结果作为 props 发送给
component itself what we want to do here is fetch the
组件本身，我们在这里要做的是
json for an individual car so it can be used in the html or ui for
获取单个汽车的 json，以便可以在 html 或
the cart page in this case we need the id from the url
用于购物车页面的 ui在这种情况下，我们需要 url 中的 id
to know which car was requested we can get that information from the
来知道请求了哪辆车我们可以从
params argument and the function then from there we'll use the fetch api
params 参数和函数中获取该信息，然后从那里我们将使用 fetch api
to make a request to localhost to request the json file with that id
向 localhost 发出请求请求具有该 id 的 json 文件，
we can then convert it to json then the final step is to return an object
然后我们可以将其转换为 json，然后最后一步是返回一个
that has a props property where each prop can then be accessed by the
具有 props 属性的对象，然后
component up in the component code we can
组件 c 中的组件可以访问每个 prop  ode 我们可以
destructure the car prop and then use it in the jsx
解构汽车道具，然后在
which i'm doing here by adding an image tag which relies on the data fetched by
我在这里做的 jsx 中使用它
the server as the image source now if you're concerned about search
engine optimization you likely want to add an
想要
seo friendly title as well as meta tags to the head of the document
在文档的头部添加一个 seo 友好的标题和元标记，
next makes that very easy to accomplish by simply importing the head component
接下来通过简单地导入 head 组件
anything inside this component will be rendered out to the head of the document
，这个组件中的任何内容都将被渲染到文档的头部，
like in this case we add a title with the car color and id
就像在这种情况下我们 添加带有汽车颜色和 ID 的标题，
and we could also add meta tags for twitter and facebook cards if we wanted
如果我们现在想要的话，我们还可以为 twitter 和 facebook 卡片添加元标记，
to now because we're working with a dynamic
因为我们正在使用动态
route there's one other thing we have to keep in mind
路线，还有一件事我们必须牢记
and that's the fact that next has no way of knowing how many pages we actually
，这就是事实 next无法知道我们实际上
have associated to a dynamic route in order to
与动态路线关联了多少页面，以便
pre-render all the car ids next needs to know those ids in advance
预渲染所有汽车 idnext 需要提前知道这些 id，
and the way we provide that information is by implementing the get static paths
我们提供该信息的方式是通过实现 t 他获取静态路径
function this function can also request data from
函数此函数还可以
an api or database then its job is to return a
从 api或数据库请求数据然后它的工作是返回一个
paths object that contains an array with every route
路径对象，该对象包含一个数组，其中包含此演示
for this dynamic url in this demo we only have three routes
中此动态 url的每个路由我们只有三个路由
tesla forward and lambo we map those values to an array of
tesla forward 和 lambo我们映射 这些值到一个对象数组，
objects then return them from the function
然后从函数中返回它们
along with additional options like the fallback behavior
以及其他选项，例如回退行为
now if we go visit the app in the browser we should see a fully rendered
现在如果我们在浏览器中访问应用程序，我们应该会看到一个完全呈现的
web page it doesn't look any different than a
网页，它看起来与常规反应没有任何不同
regular react app however if you open up the sources panel in
应用程序但是，如果您在
chrome dev tools it'll show you the fully rendered html
chrome 开发工具中打开源面板，它会在 javascript 触及之前向您显示完全渲染的 html
before it was touched by javascript notice how it contains the title
，请注意它如何包含标题
and pre-rendered content which is essential for seo
和预渲染内容，这对于 seo
and sharing content on social media sites so that's how you implement server
和在社交媒体上共享内容至关重要站点，这就是您实现服务器
side generation but another big strategy is server side
端生成的方式，但另一个重要策略是服务器端
rendering the big difference is that with ssr the
渲染，最大的区别是使用 ssr 时，
content is generated on a server when requested by the user this approach
内容是在服务器上生成的
is ideal when data changes constantly because it ensures the end user will
当数据不断变化时，这种方法是用户请求的理想选择，因为它可以确保最终用户始终
always get the latest and greatest data from whatever your data source happens
从您的数据源中获取最新和最好的数据，
to be however it's far less efficient because
但是它的效率要低得多，因为
you need to have a server in place to respond to those requests
您需要有一个适当的服务器来响应这些请求
as opposed to caching everything on a global cdn
，而不是将所有内容缓存在全球 CDN 上
imagine something like an ebay auction where you have millions of listings
想象一下像 ebay 拍卖，您有数百万个列表，
and those listings are changing all the time that's probably a good candidate
并且这些列表一直在变化，这可能是 ssr 的一个很好的候选
for ssr in any case it's very easy to
者，无论如何
implement it next back in our page file we'll go ahead and
，接下来很容易实现它回到我们的页面文件中，我们将继续
implement another function called get server side props the only
实现另一个名为 get server side props 的函数
thing that actually changes in our code is the name of the function
，我们代码中唯一实际更改的是函数的名称，
we can simply copy the body of the git static props function
我们可以简单地复制 gitstatic props 函数的主体
and paste it into our new function it does the exact same thing
并将其粘贴到 我们的新函数做了完全相同的事情，
but does it on every request instead of it build time
但是在每个请求而不是在构建时都这样做，
then we can comment out get static props and get static paths because we no
然后我们可以注释掉 get static props并 get static p  aths，因为我们
longer need those functions but the real beauty of next is that we
不再需要这些功能，但 next 的真正美妙之处在于，我们
can apply both of these paradigms wherever we want in the application
可以在应用程序中的任何我们想要的地方应用这两种范例
we're not limited to one or the other i'm going to go ahead and wrap things up
there if there's anything you want to see in my full next course
如果您想在我的完整下一门课程中看到任何内容，请
make sure to let me know in the comments thanks for watching and i will see you
务必在评论中告诉我，谢谢观看，我会在下一个课程中见到您
in the next one